<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://esposito-matteo.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://esposito-matteo.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-01-31T11:21:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esposito-matteo.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal academic profile of Matteo Esposito. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Call for Papers: QSE-NE 2024 - First International Workshop on Quantum Software Engineering: The Next Evolution</title><link href="https://esposito-matteo.github.io/blog/2024/CfP-QSENE/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call for Papers: QSE-NE 2024 - First International Workshop on Quantum Software Engineering: The Next Evolution"/><published>2024-01-24T07:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-24T07:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esposito-matteo.github.io/blog/2024/CfP-QSENE</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esposito-matteo.github.io/blog/2024/CfP-QSENE/"><![CDATA[<p>I am thrilled to announce the Call for Papers for the First International Workshop on Quantum Software Engineering: The Next Evolution (QSE-NE), happening in co-located with the ACM International Conference on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2024.</p> <h3 id="details">Details:</h3> <ul> <li>Workshop webpage: <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/qse-ne/">QSE-NE Workshop</a></li> <li>FSE 2024: <a href="https://conf.researchr.org/home/fse-2024">Conference Details</a></li> </ul> <p>The workshop aims to bring together leading researchers and practitioners in the field of Quantum Software Engineering, providing a platform for discussions that will propel this rapidly evolving field forward.</p> <h3 id="important-dates">Important Dates:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>April 10, 2024</strong>: Paper submission deadline</li> <li><strong>April 30, 2024</strong>: Authors’ notification</li> <li><strong>May 17, 2024</strong>: Camera-ready papers</li> <li><strong>July 15, 2024</strong>: Workshop takes place</li> </ul> <h3 id="submission-guidelines">Submission Guidelines:</h3> <p>For the QSE-NE 2024 workshop, we welcome the following types of submissions:</p> <ul> <li> <p><strong>Research Track (up to 10 pages):</strong> Original research papers focusing on innovative methodologies, tools, datasets, or studies aligned with the workshop themes.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Ideas, Visions, and Reflections Track (up to 4 pages):</strong> Submissions proposing radical ideas, pioneering research directions, or offering insightful reflections and lessons from past experiences.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Industry Track (up to 4 pages):</strong> Papers addressing practical industrial challenges and experiences, emphasizing real-world problems, practical insights, and lessons learned from industrial practices.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Authors are invited to submit original unpublished research papers and industrial practice papers. Simultaneous submissions to other conferences are not permitted. At least one author of accepted papers must register for the workshop to have their papers included in the FSE companion proceedings.</p> <p>Please submit your papers in PDF format <a href="https://easychair.org/conferences/?conf=qsene2024">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="CfP"/><category term="Quantum Software Engineering"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore the frontiers of Quantum Software Engineering at QSE-NE 2024, co-located with ACM FSE 2024.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring the Academic Odyssey Join Me on My Journey!</title><link href="https://esposito-matteo.github.io/blog/2023/hello-academic-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring the Academic Odyssey Join Me on My Journey!"/><published>2023-09-26T07:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-26T07:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esposito-matteo.github.io/blog/2023/hello-academic-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esposito-matteo.github.io/blog/2023/hello-academic-world/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcome-to-my-academic-blog">Welcome to My Academic Blog!</h1> <p>Hey there, and welcome to my academic blog 🤓! I’m stoked to have you drop by as I kick off this awesome adventure of sharing my research, reading recommendations, and some of my thoughts with you.</p> <p>No need for formalities; just call me Matteo :D. I’m a research enthusiast with a passion for Software Engineering. My academic path is a rollercoaster of questions, ‘aha’ moments, and loads of time nose-deep in books, articles, and data.</p> <p>So, what can you expect to find here? Well, it’s all about sharing the good stuff:</p> <ul> <li> <p><strong>Research Updates:</strong> I’ll spill the beans on my current projects from time to time. From the lightbulb moments to the nitty-gritty details, you’ll be right there with me on my research journey.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Reading Recommendations:</strong> I love a good read, and I’ll bet you do too. I’ll dish out recommendations for books, articles, and research papers that have rocked my world and inspired my work.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Insights and Musings:</strong> Ever wonder what’s rattling around in the head of a curious researcher? Here’s your chance to find out. I’ll be dishing out thoughts and reflections on everything from my research passions to the wild world of academia.</p> </li> </ul> <p>This blog isn’t a one-way street; it’s all about us learning and growing together. Your thoughts, feedback, and questions are like gold to me. We’re building a community of curious minds here, and I can’t wait to see where our conversations take us.</p> <p>Whether you’re a fellow researcher, a student on the hunt for knowledge, or just someone who’s curious about what’s cooking in my brain, you’re all welcome here. Feel free to reach out through the comments or drop me a line anytime. Let’s chat, share ideas, and explore the exciting world of academia.</p> <p>Thanks a million for joining me on this academic ride. Here’s to uncovering the wonders of knowledge together!</p> <p>Catch you on the flip side 😼!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal-posts"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my academic blog, where I'll be sharing the highs, lows, and thrilling discoveries of my research journey. Join me as I delve into the captivating world of Software Engineering, offer reading recommendations that have inspired me, and share my musings on all things academia. Let's embark on this adventure together and uncover the wonders of knowledge!]]></summary></entry></feed>